marriottvacationclub.com 2002-06-01

# Privacy Policy - Legal State Disclosures - Marriott Vacation Club International

| 

**Marriottvacationclub.com  
INTERNET PRIVACY STATEMENT **

**Introduction**

Marriott Vacation Club International has a strong commitment to providing excellent service to all of our customers, including respecting their concerns about privacy. We understand that visitors to this website may have questions about whether and how this website collects and uses information. We have prepared this statement to inform you of the privacy principles that govern Marriottvacationclub.com. Please note that a separate privacy statement and separate terms and conditions apply to the Marriott Rewards program (<http://www.marriottrewards.com/rewards/terms/privacy.asp>), although the same governing Marriott philosophy applies. 

This statement contains numerous general and technical details about the steps we take to respect your privacy concerns. The bottom line is that the needs and expectations of our customers form the foundation of everything we do – including protecting your privacy. 

**Browsing**

We have not configured this website to collect any personally identifiable information from your computer when browsing this site. This means that, unless you voluntarily provide us with personal information, we will not know your name, your e-mail address, or any other information identifiable to you. 

**Information we collect**

For each visit to our website, our Web server automatically receives various information, including the computer's IP address, operating system version, browser software version and pages browsed. 

We collect the domain name of visitors to our Web page, the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, information on what pages consumers access or visit, and information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information, site registrations, and chat conversations. 

The information we collect is used to improve the content of our website, used to customize the content and/or layout of website for individual visitors, used to notify consumers about updates to our website, and used by us to contact consumers for marketing purposes. 

We treat the information you provide to us as confidential information; it is, accordingly, subject to our company's security procedures and strict corporate policies regarding protection and use of confidential information. Because laws applicable to personal information vary by country, additional measures that vary depending on the applicable legal requirements may be put in place. Information is generally processed and stored in the United States, in which data protection laws are not as comprehensive as in the European Union. 

**Children's Privacy**

This site is not intended for children and we do not knowingly solicit or collect personal information from children. 

**Cookies**

Marriottvacationclub.com uses cookies to better serve you. We use cookies to store visitor preferences, record session information, such as which survey questions have been answered, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, alert visitors to new areas that we think might be of interest to them when they return to our site, record past activity at a site in order to provide better service when visitors return to our site, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly shown the same promotional messages, customize Web page content based on visitors' browser type or other information that the visitor sends, and to enable our live chat server to manage chat conversations. These cookies are permanent unless deleted by you. 

**E-Mail Lists**

We do not want to send you e-mail that you do not want to receive. We maintain opt-in e-mail lists for communicating general announcements, new product offerings and special offers, but you will not be added to any of these lists by visiting our web site unless you choose to do so. We may send email to current and past customers. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an e-mail to [optout@vacationclub.com](mailto:optout@vacationclub.com). Please be sure to send the e-mail from the address you wish to have deleted or if sending from a different email address, be sure to include the e-mail address you want us to delete. 

**Live Chat**

We use software that enables real time chat conversations between visitors to our web site and company representatives. Our chat software maintains a log of chat conversations that we use for supervisory and training purposes to better serve you. Web site visitors may chat by request, or our representatives may initiate chat conversations with visitors to the web site. 

**Security**

We use technologies like SSL and PGP to protect and secure the personally identifiable information you provide us. If you are using a SSL enabled browser, key forms at our web site use this capability to ensure that your information is encrypted as it travels over the Internet to our web servers. This secure mode is enabled before any such information is transmitted from your computer. 

After information reaches Marriott Vacation Club International it is stored on a secure server that resides behind a firewall that is designed to block unauthorized access from outside the Company. 

**Disclosure of Information to Third Parties**

Marriott Vacation Club International prohibits the sale or transfer of personal information to entities outside of the Marriott family of companies and hotels for their use without your approval and giving you the opportunity to opt-out. 

Marriott Vacation Club International may share your personally identifiable information with affiliated companies that are directly or indirectly controlled by, or under common control of Marriott International, Inc. 

Marriott Vacation Club International may send personally identifiable information about you to non-affiliated companies that are not directly or indirectly controlled by, or under common control of, Marriott International, Inc. when: 

  * We have your consent to share the information; 
  * We need to share your information to provide the product or service you have requested; 
  * We need to send the information to companies who work on behalf of Marriott Vacation Club International to provide a product or service to you. (These companies do not have any right to use the information we provide to them for any purpose beyond what is necessary to assist us.); 
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders or legal process; or 
  * We find that your actions on our web site violate our usage guidelines. 

**Legal Issues**

This is a United States website and is subject to United States law. Marriott Vacation Club International will disclose personal information without your permission when required by law, or in good faith belief that such action is necessary to investigate or protect against harmful activities to Marriott Vacation Club International guests, visitors, associates, or property (including this site), or to others.

 **Links to Other Sites**

If you choose to leave this website via links to other sites, Marriott Vacation Club International is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of those sites, nor is Marriott Vacation Club International responsible for the cookies those sites might deposit on your hard drive. 

**Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

In the future, we may need to change the privacy statement for Marriottvacationclub.com. All changes will be made here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. 

**Contacting Marriott Vacation Club International**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or privacy concerns, please write us at 6649 Westwood Boulevard, Suite 500, Orlando, FL 32821 or send an e-mail to [privacy@vacationclub.com](mailto:privacy@vacationclub.com).

|
